A story for everyone who works for a living.
Glengarry Glen Ross is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by James Foley.
Times are tough at Premiere Properties.
Shelley "the machine" Levene and Dave Moss are veteran
salesmen, but only Ricky Roma is on a hot streak.
The new Glengarry sales leads could turn everything around, but the front
office is holding them back until these "losers" prove themselves.
Then someone decides to take matters into his own hands, stealing the
Glengarry leads and leaving everyone wondering who did it.
Ricky Roma, played by Al Pacino.
Shelley Levene, played by Jack Lemmon.
Blake, played by Alec Baldwin.
George Aaronow, played by Alan Arkin.
Dave Moss, played by Ed Harris.
John Williamson, played by Kevin Spacey.
Glengarry Glen Ross is a 1992 American dark comedy-drama film directed by James Foley and written
by David Mamet, based on his 1984 Pulitzer Prize–winning play of the same name.
The film depicts two days in the lives of four real-estate salesmen and their increasing desperation when the corporate office
sends Blake, a motivational trainer with the threat that all but the top two salesmen will be fired within one week.
Like the play, the film is notorious for its use of profanity, leading the cast
to refer to the film jokingly as Death of a Fuckin' Salesman.
The title of the film is derived from the names of two of the fictitious real-estate
developments being peddled by the salesmen: Glengarry Highlands and Glen Ross Farms.
The film was critically acclaimed.
The world premiere was held at the 49th Venice Film Festival, where
Jack Lemmon was awarded the Volpi Cup for Best Actor.
Al Pacino was nominated for an Academy Award and a Golden
Globe Award for Best Supporting Actor.
However, the film was a box-office failure for grossing $10.7
million in North America against a $12.5 million budget.
It has since become a cult classic.
The film explores themes of estate agent, robbery,
competition, office, dark comedy.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.